Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
- South Africa Compiled from the M.S. Maps in the Colonial Office. -- London: Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge (Great Britain); Owen, W. F. W., 1774-1857; Owen, W. F. W., 1774-1857, 1834; NOR 0193; : Colored; 31 cm. x 39 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Insets of Environs of the Cape district, District of George, Environs of Graham-Town and Cape-Town.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0193, p. 218
  Norwich number: 0193
  RID: MOA 0178
- Neueste Karte von Sud Africa Nach den besten Quellen entworf und gezeichn von ... = Latest map of Africa drawn from reliable information by ... --: Meyer, Joseph, 1796-1856; Radefeld, Carl Christian Franz, 1788-1874, 1846; NOR 0194; Steel: Outline color; 29 cm. x 36 cm.
  Source: Meyer's Neuste Universal Handatlas
  Descriptive Notes: "An accurate and detailed map, especially of the Cape Colony and Kafferland." Insets of, the Eastern Cap Coast, District of George, Cape Peninsula and Cape Town; Prime meridian through Paris and Ferro Island. Top left: Meyers Handatlas. Top right: No. 93.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0194, p. 219
  Norwich number: 0194
  RID: MOA 0163
- Colton's Africa: southern sheet. -- New York: Colton, J. H. (Joseph Hutchins), 1800-1893; Colton, J. H. (Joseph Hutchins), 1800-1893, 1855; NOR 0195; : Colored; 28.5 cm. x 35.5 cm.
  Source: World Atlas
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Washington; Bottom right: No. 36.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0195, p. 220
  Norwich number: 0195
  RID: MOA 0260
- Map of South Africa illustrating Dr. Livingstone's Discoveries. -- London: Pepper, W.; Pepper, W. Exploration, 1858; NOR 0196; manuscript: Outline color; 35 cm. x 47 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Dr. Livingstone "was the first European to cross the African continent ... ". Map illustrates exploration routes of Livingston's journeys.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0196, p. 221
  Norwich number: 0196
  RID: MOA 0210
- Southern Africa comprising Cape Colony, Natal c. with Orange River Free States. -- Edinburgh: William Blackwood and Sons; Johnston, Alexander Keith, 1804-1871; Johnston, Alexander Keith, 1804-1871, 1862; NOR 0197; : Colored; 28 cm. x 44 cm.
  Source: General Atlas
  Descriptive Notes: This map is in two parts, northwest Africa, shows mountain ranges, river and coastal inlets. The southern portion illustrates greater detail than Johnston's earlier map (see NOR 0145). Top right: Keith Johnston's General Atlas; Bottom right: 38.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0197, p. 222
  Norwich number: 0197
  RID: MOA 0198
- South Africa by Jas Wyld, Geographer to the Queen and H.R. H. Prince Albert. -- London Wyld, James, 1812-1887, 1844; NOR 0198; : Outline color; 52 cm. x 82 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Part of a series of South African maps, (see NOR 0199, NOR 0200, NOR 0201) illustrating the growing settlements in colored outline. Verso: 32.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0198, p. 223
  Norwich number: 0198
  RID: MOA 0290
  Africa -- South Africa -- 19th c.
- South Africa by Jas Wyld, Geographer to the Queen and H.R. H. Prince Albert. -- London Wyld, James, 1812-1887, 1854-1861; NOR 0199; : Outline color; 52 cm. x 82 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Part of a series of South African maps, (see NOR 0198, NOR 0200, NOR 0201). Verso: 56.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0199, p. 225
  Norwich number: 0199
  RID: MOA 0291
- South Africa by Jas Wyld, Geographer to the Queen and H.R.H. Prince Albert. -- London Wyld, James, 1812-1887, 1855; NOR 0200; : Outline color; 53 cm. x 83.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Part of a series of South African maps, (see NOR 0198, NOR 0199, NOR 0201). Verso: 32.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0200, p. 226
  Norwich number: 0200
  RID: MOA 0292
- South Africa by Jas Wyld, Geographer to the Queen. -- London Wyld, James, 1812-1887, 1886; NOR 0201; : Outline color; 52 cm. x 82 cm
  Descriptive Notes: Part of a series of South African maps, (see NOR 0198, NOR 0199, NOR 0200). Verso: 33.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0210, p. 227
  Norwich number: 0210
  RID: MOA 0293
- Cape of Good Hope, Natal c. -- London: Weller, Edward, d. 1884; Weller, Edward, d. 1884; Weller, Edward, d. 1884, 1858; NOR 0202; : Outline color; 43.5 cm. x 63.4 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Borders of subdivisions are shown in printed colors; Prime meridian thourgh Greenwich. Bottom left: Weekly Despatch Atlas. 139 Fleet Street.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0202, p. 228
  Norwich number: 0202
  RID: MOA 0249
  Africa -- Cape of Good Hope -- 19th c.
- South Africa, From Official and other authentic Authorities. -- Edinburgh: A. Fullarton Co.; Fullarton, Archibald; Fullarton, Archibald, 1870-72; NOR 0203; : Colored; 40 cm. x 52 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Peninsula of the Cape; Prime meridian through Greenwich. Top left and right: No. 65.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0203, p. 229
  Norwich number: 0203
  RID: MOA 0230
- Map of South Africa. -- Unknown: Rand, McNally Co.; Rand, McNally Co., 1892; NOR 0204; : Colored; 48.5 cm. x 66.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Historic sites are illustrated, such as the diamond fields of Griqualand West. Title across top: Rand, McNally Company's Indexed Atlas of the World. Top left: 138. Top right: 139; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0204, p. 230
  Norwich number: 0204
  RID: MOA 0311
- Delineatio Promontorii, Quod Cabo de bona Esperanca vulgo vocatur. = Map of the promontory known as Cape of Good Hope. -- Frankfurt: Bry, Theodor de, 1528-1598; Bry, Theodor de, 1528-1598; Bry, Theodor de, 1528-1598, NOR 0205; : Uncolored; 14 cm. x 17 cm.
  Source: Petits Voyages (1598)
  Descriptive Notes: The seas contain sea monsters, sailing ships, natives paddling a canoe and two compass roses. Part of folio map with Latin text on bottom. "The map also appears in Indiae Orientalis Pars, IX (Verhoefs voyage to the Moluccas, 1607-1609), by de Bry, published in Frankfurt in 1612, with a Latin edition 1607-1612." Top right: III. Bottom right: GK.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0205, p. 232
  Norwich number: 0205
  RID: MOA 0036
  Africa -- Cape of Good Hope -- 16th c.
- Nieuwe Naaukeurige Land-en Zee-Kaart, van het voornaamste Gedeelte der Kaffersche Kust, Begrypende de Sardanje-Bay en de Caap de Bonne Esperanca met alle des Zelfs Plantazien. = New and accurate map and sea chart of the Cape coast from Saldanha Bay to the Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam, 1688-1702; NOR 0207; : Uncolored; 57 cm. x 48 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Title across top: Nova et Accurata Tabula Promontorii Bonae Spei vulgo Cabo de Bona Esperanca; Prime meridian through Tenerife. Compiled by Ottens, Joachim, 1663-1719.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0207, p. 234
  Norwich number: 0207
  RID: MOA 0125
- A Map of the Cape of Good Hope with its true Situation. -- London Nieuhof, Johannes, 1618-1672 Exploration, 1703; NOR 0209; : Colored; 27 cm. x 35 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map shows "early routes of one of the early exploring expeditions." Mainland is decorated with various animals, elephants, lion, snakes, ostriches, cows and sheep. The seas contain several sailing vessels and a compass rose. Inset: View of Table Mountain. Top left: Vol. 2 p. 141.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0209, p. 236
  Norwich number: 0209
  RID: MOA 0152
- Vue et Description du Cap de Bonne Esperance. = View and description of the Cape of Good Hope. -- Paris: Chatelain, Henri Abraham; Gueudeville, Nicolas, ca. 1654-ca. 1721.; Chatelain, Henri Abraham, 1705-1720; NOR 0210; Copperplate: Uncolored; 35.5 cm. x 21 cm.
  Source: Atlas Historique et Methodique (1705-20)
  Descriptive Notes: Two views of the Cape. Inset: Le fort des Hollandois au Cap du Bonne Esperance. Top right: Tom. VI, No. 17, Pag. 74.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0210, p. 237
  RID: MOA 0037
- Cap de Bonne Esperance. = Cape of Good Hope. -- Paris: Fer, Nicolas de, 1646-1720; Fer, Nicolas de, 1646-1720, 1705; NOR 0211; Copperplate: Uncolored; 24.5 cm. x 35 cm.
  Source: Atlas Curieux
  Descriptive Notes: Insets: Table Bay and a whaling station, the other a ground-plan of the Fort. Top right: 327.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0211, p. 238
  Norwich number: 0211
  RID: MOA 0128
- Le Cap de Bonne Esperance Suivant les Nouvelles Observations de Messrs. de l'Academie Royale des Sciences ... = Cape of Good Hope according to the observations made by the Royal Academy of Science. -- Leiden: Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1773; Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1773, 1713; NOR 0212; : Uncolored; 22.5 cm. x 29.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Cartouche is "on a stone pediment surmounted by a lion and lioness, with a view of Table Bay in the background and the Governor's garden and homestead." Map includes a note describing the Cape of Good Hope and a legend explaining the contents of the mainland.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0212, p. 239
  Norwich number: 0212
  RID: MOA 0142
- Niuewe Kaart van Caap der Goode Hoop in hare rechte jegenwoordige staat vertoond door ... = New map of the Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: van Braam, J. and onder de Linden, G.; Valentijn, Francois, 1656-1727, 1724-1726; NOR 0214; : Uncolored; 44 cm. x 56 cm.
  Source: Valentijn's Oud en Nieuw Oost Indien, vol. 5 (1724-1726)
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Detail of the Cape Peninsula with names of farms and their owners. Top right: No. 43. This map "served as a source for other map makers over a number of years."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0214, p. 241
  Norwich number: 0214
  RID: MOA 0134
- Gezicht van Kaap der Goede Hope, als men op de Reede legt. = View of the Cape of Good Hope ... -- Amsterdam: van Braam, J. and onder de Linden, G.; Valentijn, Francois, 1656-1727, 1726; NOR 0215; : Uncolored; 27 cm. x 36 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Pieter van de Aa's map (see NOR 0216). Each mountain is numbered with an accompanying legend. Border: 1. 't Vlek. 2. de Tafel-berg. 3. de Wind-berg. 4. de Leeuwen-bert. Top right: No. 38. C.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0215, p. 242
  Norwich number: 0215
  RID: MOA 0153
- Le Cape de Bonne Esperance comme il a ete ci-devant. = The Cape of God Hope ... -- Leiden: Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1733; Aa, Pieter van der, 1659-1733, 1727; NOR 0216; Copperplate: Uncolored; 28.5 cm. x 34 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Valentijn' s map (see NOR 0215). The mountains are numbered and named in the border. 1. Le chateau. 2. Le Petit-Fort. 3. Montagne du lion. 4. Montagne de la Table. 5. Montagne du Vent. 6. Endroit ou tous les Bataeux Viennent.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0216, p. 243
  Norwich number: 0216
  RID: MOA 0154
- Carta Geographica del Capo de Buona Speranza. = Map of the Cape of Good Hope. -- Venice: L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, 1740-1756; NOR 0218; : Colored; 32 cm. x 42 cm.
  Source: Atlante Novissimo Che Contiene tutti le parti del Mondo (1740-1756)
  Descriptive Notes: Example of a popular L'Isle map, which others copied. Map "shows the routes from the Cape inland to the kraals of the various tribes, sweet water wells, salt pans, woods, rivers, and many of the early farming settlements." Inset: Spiegazione.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0218, p. 245
  Norwich number: 0218
  RID: MOA 0168
- Nieuwe Kaart van de Kaap der Goede Hoope en der na by gelegen Landen volgens de Afmeetingen van den Abt. de la Caille in 1752. = New map of the Cape of Good Hope and surrounding country ... -- Amsterdam: Tirion, Isaak; Tirion, Isaak, 1763; NOR 0221; : Colored; 31.5 cm. x 21.5 cm.
  Source: Nieuwe en Beknopte Handatlas (1744-69)
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Paris and Tenerife.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0221, p. 248
  Norwich number: 0221
  RID: MOA 0172
- Il Paese Degli ottentotti ne' Contorni del Capo di Buona Speranza. = The land of the Hottentots ... the Cape of Good Hope. -- Paris: Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772; Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772, 1781; NOR 0222; : Uncolored; 24.5 cm. x 34.5 cm.
  Source: Teatro della Guerra Maritime (1781)
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0222, p. 249
  Norwich number: 0222
  RID: MOA 0093
- The Dutch Colony of the Cape of Good Hope. -- London: Faden, William; Delarochette, L.; Delarochette, L., 1795; NOR 0225; : Uncolored; 50 cm. x 33 cm.
  Source: William Faden's Atlas (1795)
  Descriptive Notes: The title of the cartouche is on a cliff, nearby are palms, natives on horseback and an elephant; Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0225, p. 252
  Norwich number: 0225
  RID: MOA 0126
- Southern coast of Africa. -- London: Cadell Davies; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823, 1803; NOR 0227; : Uncolored; 25.5 cm. x 41 cm.
  Source: Untitled atlas containing maps of Africa (1803)
  Descriptive Notes: Part of a series of four double-paged linen backed coastal map. Inset: Table Bay and False Bay.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0227, p. 254
  Norwich number: 0227
  RID: MOA 0081
  Africa -- South Coast of Africa -- 19th c.
- A New Chart of False Bay. -- Unknown Cruger, S. Sea chart, 1808; NOR 0230; : Uncolored; 35 cm. x 30.5 cm.
  Source: Marine Atlas or Seamen's Complete Pilot (1808)
  Descriptive Notes: Includes numerous soundings and rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0230, p. 257
  Norwich number: 0230
  RID: MOA 0135
  Oceans -- False Bay -- 19th c.
- A Military Sketch of that part of the Colony of the Cape of Good Hope, Bordering on the Caffres and most exposed to their Depredations with the different Military Posts, Roads, Rivers c. -- London: Faden, William, 1750?-1836; Faden, William, 1750?-1836; Faden, William, 1750?-1836; Wily, Lieut. Military, 1818; NOR 0232; : Uncolored; 60 cm. x 48 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "A legend refers in detail to military posts, posts with farms, troops' quarters, villages." Inset: Note on the Great Fish River.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0232, p. 259
  Norwich number: 0232
  RID: MOA 0279
- Survey of the Cape of Good Hope by Lieut. A.T.E. Vidal of HMS Leven assisted by Capt. Lechmere, Lt. T. Boteler and Mr. M.H.A. Gibbons under the direction of ... 1882. -- London: Hydrographical Office of Admiralty; Owen, W. F. W., 1774-1857; Owen, W. F. W., 1774-1857, 1828; NOR 0234; : Uncolored; 59 cm. x 43 cm.
  Source: Narrative of Voyages to Explore the Shores of Africa, Arabia and Madagascar (vol. 2, 1883)
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Dias Rock and Cape Hangklip. Bottom right: 636.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0234, p. 261
  Norwich number: 0234
  RID: MOA 0133
- Map of the Eastern Frontier of the Colony of the Cape of Good Hope. -- London: Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823; Chase, John Centlivres, 1838; NOR 0235; : Colored; 50.5 cm. x 58 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: First published in 1836 by John Arrowsmith of London. "This map provides a great deal of historical and geographical information regarding the important part of the Cape Colony which was the scene of nine frontier wars between the Cape government and the Xhosa tribe." Inset shows 'Statistical notes 1833'. Dedicated to Sir Benjamin D'Urban.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0235, p. 262
  Norwich number: 0235
  RID: MOA 0119
  Africa -- Eastern Africa -- 19th c.
- Cape District, Cape of Good Hope. -- London: Wyld, James, 1812-1887; Delarochette, L, 1838; NOR 0236; : Uncolored; 50.5 cm. x 33 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: First published by Delarochette in 1782. Second edition in 1795 (see NOR 0225).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0236, p. 264
  Norwich number: 0236
  RID: MOA 0139
  Africa -- Cape District -- 19th c.
- Cape Colony. -- London: Tallis, John, 1815 or 6-1876; Tallis, John, 1815 or 6-1876; Tallis, John, 1815 or 6-1876; Warren, H., 1851; NOR 0237; Steel: Outline color; 24 cm. x 32 cm.
  Source: Illustrated Atlas and Modern History of the World (1851)
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Cape Town, entrance to Knysna and Graham's Town. Illustrations engraved by Bond, H. W., fl. 1827-1849; Prime meridian through Greenwich.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0237, p. 265
  Norwich number: 0237
  RID: MOA 0187
  Africa -- Cape Colony -- 19th c.
- Typus orarum maritimarum Guinae, Manicongo Angloae ultra promontorium Bonae Spei ... = Marine map of Guinea, Manicongo and Angola to the Cape of Good Hope ... -- Amsterdam: Langren, Arnold Florent van, 1580-1644; Langren, Arnold Florent van, 1580-1644; Langren, Arnold Florent van, 1580-1644 Sea chart, 1596; NOR 0239a; : Uncolored; 38 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Companion map to NOR 0239b, which form a map of Africa and the surrounding seas. This map is from the Dutch edition published in 1596. The sea contains two compass roses. Inset: Views of Ascension and St. Helena.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0239a, p. 274
  Norwich number: 0239a
  RID: MOA 0146
  Oceans -- Islands -- 16th c.
- Delineatio Orarum maritimarum Terrae vulgo indigitatae Terra do Natal item Sofala Mozambicae Melindae ... = Marine map of Natal, Sofala, Mozambique and Melinde ... -- London: Wolfe, John, d. 1601; Langren, Arnold Florent van, 1580-1644; Langren, Arnold Florent van, 1580-1644 Sea chart, 1598; NOR 0239b; : Uncolored; 38 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Companion map to NOR 0239a. This map is from the Dutch edition, published in 1596. Seas contain several compass roses with radiating rhumb lines, ships, whales and dolphins.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0239, p. 275
  Norwich number: 0239b
  RID: MOA 0145
- Mar di Aethiopia vulgo Oceanus Aethiopicus. = Sea chart of the Atlantic Ocean. -- Amsterdam: Jansson, Jan, 1588-1664; Jansson, Jan, 1588-1664 Sea chart, 1650; NOR 0240; : Colored; 43 cm. x 56 cm.
  Source: Atlantis Majoris (1650)
  Descriptive Notes: Extends eastward to include South America. The compass rose radiates numerous rhumb lines. "An elongated land mass along the lower border is labelled Terra Australis Incognita probably one of the earliest representations of Australia."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0240, p. 276
  Norwich number: 0240
  RID: MOA 0155
  Oceans -- Sea chart -- 17th c.
- Oost Indien van Cabo de Bona Esperanca tot Ceilon. = East Indies from Cape of Good Hope to Ceylon. -- Amsterdam: Colom, Arnold; Colom, Arnold Sea chart, 1654; NOR 0241; : Colored; 63 cm. x 54 cm.
  Source: Zee Atlas (1654)
  Descriptive Notes: "The top of the cartouche shows a large open-mouthed animal with its fangs overlapping the top edge." The Indian Ocean contain two compass roses with radiating rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0241, p. 277
  Norwich number: 0241
  RID: MOA 0193
- Tabula transitus Gibraltaris cum Portibus Hispanicis usq. Malagam. = Map of the Straits of Gibraltar, Spanish and Barbary coasts. -- Frankfurt: Merian, Matthaeus, 1593-1650; Merian, Matthaeus, 1593-1650 Sea chart, No date; NOR 0242; : Colored; 26 cm. x 36 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: A sailing ship is illustrated alongside a compass rose.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0242, p. 278
  Norwich number: 0242
  RID: MOA 0160
- Pas-karte van de Zuyd-west-kust van Africa; van Cabo Negro tot beoosten Cabo de Bona Esperanca. = Map of the south-west coast of Africa from Cape Negro to Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: Goos, Pieter, ca. 1616-1675; Goos, Pieter, ca. 1616-1675 Sea chart, No date; NOR 0243; Copperplate: Uncolored; 29 cm. x 52 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Identical sea chart by Jodocus Hondius appeared in Klare Besgryving van Cabo de Bona Esperanca of 1652. The sea contains a north-pointing compass rose. Inset: Vlees Bay and Cape of Good Hope.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0243, p. 279
  Norwich number: 0243
  RID: MOA 0127
  Oceans -- Cape of Good Hope -- 17th c.
- Pascaerte van't Westelycke Deel van Oost Indien, van Cabo de Bona Esperanca tot C. Comorin. = Map of the western part of the East Indies from the Cape of Good Hope to Cape Comorin. -- Amsterdam: Goos, Pieter, ca. 1616-1675; Goos, Pieter, ca. 1616-1675 Sea chart, 1654; NOR 0244; : Outline color; 44 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The sea is decorated with two sailing vessels and one compass rose with rhumb lines that extend over southern Arabia and the west coast of India. Cartouche includes two Africans in oriental costume and four children.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0244, p. 280
  Norwich number: 0244
  RID: MOA 0266
  Africa -- Sea chart -- 17th c.
- Carta particolare che comincia con il Capo Degortam e con il capo Buona Speranza e finisce in Gradi 27 di Latitudine Australe. = Map of South Africa from Cape Degortam round the Cape of Good Hope to lat. 27 degrees S. -- Florence: Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649 Sea chart, 1646-7; NOR 0245; : Uncolored; 46 cm. x 73 cm.
  Source: Arcano del Mare (1646-7, Book VI)
  Descriptive Notes: The interior remains almost blank with the exception of three mountain ranges. The bays and capes are marked.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0245, p. 282
  Norwich number: 0245
  RID: MOA 0295
- Carta Seconda Generale d'Affrica. = Map of southern Africa. -- Florence: Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649 Sea chart, 1646-7; NOR 0246; : Uncolored; 45 cm. x 72 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Second version of Dudley's southern Africa. Extends from Ethiopia to Quiloa. Inset: Somaliland.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0246, p. 283
  Norwich number: 0246
  RID: MOA 0296
  Oceans -- Southern Africa -- 17th c.
- Carta particolareche mostra il Capo buona Speranza con il Mare Verso Ponte e con L'isole di Tristan D'Acunha e di Martin Vaz. = Map showing the Cape of Good Hope and islands of Tristan da Cunha and Martin Vaz. -- Florence: Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649 Sea chart, 1646-7; NOR 0247; : Uncolored; 47 cm. x 74 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Calligraphy covers much of the South Atlantic. A compass rose and two sailing vessels decorate the sea.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0247, p. 284
  Norwich number: 0247
  RID: MOA 0324
- Carta particolare della parte Australle della Esola S. Lorenzo con la terra ferma dirinpetto e Finisce con Gradi 6. di Latitudine Australe. = East coast of Africa with the southern part of the Island of Madagascar. -- Florence: Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649 Sea chart, 1646-7; NOR 0248; : Uncolored; 47 cm. x 75 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Portuguese settlements and rivers and bays are indicated on the coastlines. The sea contains a compass rose and one sailing vessel.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0248, p. 285
  Norwich number: 0248
  RID: MOA 0323